RIFAT BIN SIRAJ

Software Engineer

rifatrabbi024@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/rifatbinsiraj



github.com/Rifat024

+8801761233953



Aftabnagar, Dhaka, Bangladesh



SUMMARY

I am a highly skilled and motivated software developer with 2.5 years of experience in developing desktop, web applications. For a career objective for a software engineer, you can include pointers such as I am seeking a position with a company where I can use my skills to positively impact the business.

PROJECTS

1. Hotel Booking Management System for Admin:

- **Key Features:** Overview of the entire system. Bill calculation, and
- payment method integration.
- **Technology:** Spring-Boot, Postgresql, AWS S3, EC2, CI/CD.
- Live Url: Internal use.

2. Hotel Booking Management System for Merchants

- **Key Features:** Overview of the entire system. Bill calculation, Merchant Payout calculation, and payment method integration.
- **Technology:** Spring-boot, Postgresql, firebase auth, AWS S3, EC2, CI/CD.
- Live Url: https://partner.ghuddy.com

3. Hotel Booking Management System for Users

- **Key Features:** Overview of the entire system. Bill calculation, and payment method integration.
- **Technology:** Spring-Boot, Postgresql, firebase auth, AWS S3, EC2, CI/CD.
- Live Url: https://ghuddy.com

4. Company Management

- **Key Features:** Overview of the entire system. Payment calculation, employment management, and timesheet management.
- **Technology:** Serverless, Node.js, React.js, DynamoDB. Lambda, API gateway, SNS, SES.
- Live Url: Internal use.

5. API Test Suite

- Key Features: Test APIs like Postmen Web.
- Technology: Serverless, Node.js, React.js, DynamoDB. Lambda, API gateway, SNS, SES.
- Live Url: Internal use.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer

Sense & Respond Software LLC | 2022 - Present

- Build dynamic, visually attractive, end-to-end, and innovative software products/apps including front-end and back-end
- Able to design the user experience, user interaction, responsive design, and complete architecture
- Able to work with databases, servers, APIs, version control systems, and third-party apps
- .

Software Engineer

Ghuddy Limited | 2021 - 2022

- Write code and tests, build prototypes, resolve issues, and profile and analyze bottlenecks
- Manage and optimize scalable distributed systems in the cloud
- Optimize web applications for performance and scalability
- Develop automated tests to ensure business needs are met, and allow for regression testing
- Write code and tests, build prototypes, resolve issues, and profile and analyze bottlenecks

SKILLS

- Java(Spring Boot)
- Javascript (NodeJS, Serverless)
- SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, NoSQL)
- AWS, Lambda, SNS, SES, DynamoDB, API-Getway, S3, Cognito
- Unix, Git

EDUCATION

Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science & Engineering 2016 – 2021